{"tossups": [{"question": "During this event, one man issued the Fort Hill letter and another document that supported a \"concurrent majority.\" The state of Virginia sent Benjamin Leigh to dissuade one side in this event, which saw a ship belonging to James Hamilton Jr. be seized by federal troops stationed at Fort Moultrie. This event, which was almost ended by the Verplanck Bill, led to the passage of the Force Act. The South Carolina Exposition and Protest was written by John C. Calhoun during this event, which was ended by the Tariff of 1833. For 10 points, name this crisis during the Jackson administration, which encompassed South Carolina's reaction to the Tariff of Abominations", "answer": "Nullification Crisis", "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Nullification Crisis</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Nullification Crisis"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This man proved the uniqueness of a function's representation as a trigonometric series, and he's the second namesake of a theorem that states that any continuous function from a compact space to another metric space is uniformly continuous. The first of Hilbert's twenty-three problems was proposed by this man and states that there is no set whose cardinality is strictly between that of the integers and reals. This man's namesake theorem states that for any set A, the cardinality of its power set is larger.   This man used his namesake diagonal argument to show that there are an infinite number of sets for which a bijection cannot be created with the set of natural numbers. For 10 points, name this mathematician who came up with the Continuum Hypothesis and created Na\u00c3\u00afve Set theory.", "answer": "Georg Cantor", "subcategory": "Math", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Georg Cantor</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Georg Cantor"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This work claims that the morality of Maggie Tulliver in The Mill on the Floss has the same origin as the desire of La Sanseverina in The Charterhouse of Parma. This work considers a young man whose brother is killed by enemy forces, concluding that Kantian and Christian ethics cannot help him decide whether to join the army or tend to his bereaved mother. Martin Heidegger responded to this work in a famous letter to his student Jean Beaufret. This work begins by responding to the Communists' accusations of quietism, then goes on to rehabilitate the ideas of \"abandonment\" and \"anguish.\" This work, originally delivered as a lecture at the Club Maintenant, coined the phrase \"existence precedes essence.\" For 10 points, name this Jean-Paul Sartre essay, which explains the applicability of his philosophy.", "answer": "\"Existentialism is a Humanism\" [or \"The Humanism of Existentialism\"; or \"L'Existentialisme est une Humanisme\"]", "category": "Philosophy", "subcategory": "Philosophy", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>\"Existentialism is a Humanism\"</u></b> [or <b><u>The Humanism of Existentialism</u></b>; or <b><u>L'Existentialisme est une Humanisme</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["\"Existentialism is a Humanism\"", "The Humanism of Existentialism", "L'Existentialisme est une Humanisme"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One character in this opera has no lines except for whispering \"and in other places\" into his boss's ear. The closing scene of this opera reprises the melody from a barcarolle at the start of the second act about the poor girl Nina, who is beloved by the rich senator Tredenti. The protagonist of this opera wonders whether he should enlist in the army for quick money in the aria \"Venti Scudi,\" although in reality he has just inherited a fortune from his dead uncle. The female lead sings \"Della crudele Isotta\" after reading the story of  Tristan and Isolde. That character decides to marry Sergeant Belcore as soon as possible when she feels ignored by the protagonist. When the protagonist of this opera realizes that Adina is in love with him, he sings the aria \"Una furtiva lagrima.\" For 10 points, name this opera in which Dr. Dulcamara sells Nemorino the title potion, composed by Gaetano Donizetti.", "answer": "The Elixir of Love [or L'Elisir d'amore]", "subcategory": "Other Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>The Elixir of Love</u></b> [or <b><u>L'Elisir d'amore</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["The Elixir of Love", "L'Elisir d'amore"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In one of this author's stories, a Prioress schemes to marry her nephew Boris to the unwilling Athena Hopballehus in order to hide his homosexuality. In another story by this author of \"The Monkey\", Fanny and Eliza learn about their brother Morton's adventures while conversing with his ghost. In another work by this author, the narrator teaches the young boy Kamante to cook after failing to heal the sores on his legs. This author of \"The Supper at Elsinore\" described burying the hunter Denys Finch-Hatton after his death in a plane crash in her most famous work. For 10 points, name this author of Seven Gothic Tales, who described her years on a coffee plantation in Kenya in Out of Africa.", "answer": "Isak Dinesen [or Karen Blixen]", "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Isak <b><u>Dinesen</u></b> [or <b><u>Karen Blixen</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Isak Dinesen", "Karen Blixen"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The score for this piece originally called for an ophicleide and a serpent, two brass instruments now usually replaced with tubas. At the beginning and end of this piece's third movement, and English horn plays a ranz de vaches: the first time it is answered by the oboe, but the second it is darkly answered by four timpani imitating a thunderstorm. The last movement of this piece features the first solo for an E-flat clarinet in a symphonic orchestra rather than a military band, and contains a parody of the Dies Irae that is intermingled with diabolical dance music. The composer of this work later wrote a kind of sequel to it called Lelio. It begins with the movement \"Reveries-Passions,\" and the last two movements depict the central figure's dreams after he poisons himself with opium. For 10 points, name this piece containing a recurring id\u00c3\u00a9e fixe representing Harriet Smithson, the most famous work of Hector Berlioz.", "answer": "Symphonie Fantastique: \u00c3\u2030pisode de la vie d'un Artiste...en cinq parties [or Fantastic Symphony: An Episode in the Life of an Artist, in Five Parts]", "subcategory": "Auditory Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Symphonie Fantastique: \u00c3\u2030pisode de la vie d'un Artiste...en cinq parties</u></b> [or <b><u>Fantastic Symphony: An Episode in the Life of an Artist, in Five Parts</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Symphonie Fantastique: \u00c3\u2030pisode de la vie d'un Artiste...en cinq parties", "Fantastic Symphony: An Episode in the Life of an Artist, in Five Parts"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One character in this film is disdainful of the fire in gunpowder, and another character melts into green goo after his hair changes from blond to red. Some of the battleships in this movie travel by flapping wings. The protagonist of this film offers to help a character voiced by Lauren Bacall up a long set of stairs, as the very large woman has sweat dripping from her multiple necks. The title location of this movie includes a color dial with options that cause the front door to open in different places, including the Waste, where the protagonist encounters a scarecrow she names \"Turnip-head.\" This movie's title wizard lives with his apprentice Markl and the demon Calcifer. For 10 points, name this 2004 film directed by Hayao Miyazaki in which Sophie is transformed into an old woman.", "answer": "Howl's Moving Castle", "category": "Trash", "subcategory": "Trash", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Howl's Moving Castle</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Howl's Moving Castle"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "John Augustine Collins was wounded during the early stages of this battle, and before this battle one commander asked to allow his forces to become \"flowers of death\". During this battle, the Darto and Dace destroyed several enemies in the Palawan Passage. One commander in this battle was criticized for not detaching Task Force 34 to help Thomas Kinkaid. This battle, which took place a few months after the Great Marianas Turkey Shoot, saw action at Cape Engano and the Suriago Strait. The Third Fleet under William Halsey destroyed Kurita's \"Center Force\" in this battle, including the battleship Musashi. This battle saw the first kamikaze attacks, and by tonnage it's the largest naval battle in history. For 10 points, name this 1944 WWII pacific theatre battle fought off a namesake island in the Philippines.", "answer": "Battle of Leyte Gulf", "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Battle of Leyte Gulf</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Battle of Leyte Gulf"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Jaffrey and Page developed an RNA mimic of this protein called the 24-2 aptamer. It's not ubiqtuitin or anything Gal4-related, but a split version of this protein is be used for bimolecular complementation assay as a replacement for FRET systems. This protein contains an HBI molecule that ionizes to a phenolate upon correct cyclization of the serine-65-tyrosine-66-glycine-67 motif. The calcium-binding protein Aqueorin associates with it in vivo. This protein contains a beta-barrel motif surrounding its active site. Assays with this protein commonly use a confocal microscope. This protein was discovered by Shimamura in jellyfish, and was refined by Tsien, who mutated it into several different colors. For 10 points, identify this useful reporter protein that glows its namesake color.", "answer": "GFP or Green fluorescent protein", "subcategory": "Biology", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>GFP or Green fluorescent protein</u></b>", "acceptable": ["GFP or Green fluorescent protein"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This poem alludes to the poet's persecution when the speaker notes that he is \"followed in [his] imagination by [a] detective.\" The speaker of this work parenthetically confesses, \"I touch your book and dream of our odyssey\u00c2\u2026and feel absurd.\"  At the end of this poem, the speaker imagines his \"courage-teacher\" getting out on a \"smoking bank\" and watching Charon's boat disappear. This poem mourns the \"lost America of love\" and describes a \"lonely old grubber\" who asks \"Are you my angel?\" The speaker of this poem sees Garcia Lorca among the watermelons before seeing another poet \"poking among the meats\" and \"eyeing the grocery boys.\" For 10 points, name this poem in which Allen Ginsberg imagines walking with Walt Whitman through the title store.", "answer": "\"A Supermarket in California\"", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>\"A Supermarket in California\"</u></b>", "acceptable": ["\"A Supermarket in California\""], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This god cursed Tulsi to be reincarnated as an herb after she begged this god to marry her. After this figure's birth, Sani initially refused to look at him because of his wife's curse that his gaze would destroy anything in its path. This god once cursed the moon god after the latter saw him fall off his mount and break open his stomach, which was full of the sweets he loved to eat. This god married Buddhi and Siddhi after he won a race around the world against his brother Karttikeya by reading scriptures while his brother physically traveled. Vyasa dictated the Mahabharata to this god, who travels on a rat. This god, who travels on a rat, refused to dodge a blow from his father's trident while this remover of obstacles was guarding his mother's bath. For 10 points, name this elephant-headed son of Shiva and Parvati.", "answer": "Ganesha", "category": "Mythology", "subcategory": "Mythology", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Ganesha</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Ganesha"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Brian Sewell claims to have masturbated in the left armpit of this man's Debris Christ. He painted a crucified Jesus at an extreme angle hovering over a boat and some fisherman in another work. In addition to painting Christ of Saint John of the Cross, this man depicted a painter from an earlier era with an extremely long leg in front of a brick wall, and another of his works shows a woman, with a grasshopper on her, giving a man with cuts on his knees fellatio. In addition to The Ghost of Vermeer of Delft and The Great Masturbator, this man painted a \"Disintegration of\" his most famous painting, which depicts yellow cliffs in the background, while ants crawl over an orange melting watch in the foreground. For 10 points, name this painter of The Persistence of Memory.", "answer": "Salvador Dali", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Salvador Dali</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Salvador Dali"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This law is often used alongside the method of images when dealing with plate barriers. One application of this law can be used to show that a person inside a planet is only pulled by the gravity of the ground beneath him and not above. A modification of one version of this law sets one side of it equal to mu nought times row m instead of 0 and allows for magnetic monopoles. The differential and integral forms of this law are equal according the divergence theorem, which was also discovered by this law's namesake. One version of this law states that the divergence of the electric field is equal to the charge density over the permittivity of free space; or that the electric flux through a closed surface is equal to the enclosed charge over the permittivity of free space. For 10 points, give this law, whose electrical and magnetic versions form half of Maxwell's equations for electromagnetism.", "answer": "Gauss's Law ", "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Gauss's Law</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Gauss's Law"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In one story by this author, the narrator discovers that his old friend Amilamia is crippled, and her parents, pretending she is dead, have placed the title effigy in her bed. In another work by this author of \"The Doll Queen,\" the protagonist takes over the estate of his father-in-law, Don Gamaliel, and is grieved when his son Lorenzo dies in the Spanish Civil War. He wrote a novel describing the ancient witch Consuelo, who uses herbs to create a younger image of herself and seduces the historian Felipe Montero. This author of Aura described the execution of the Indian Regina and the death of Gonzalo Bernal in a stream-of-consciousness novel comprising the recollections of the title businessman. For 10 points, name this Mexican author of The Death of Artemio Cruz.", "answer": "Carlos Fuentes ", "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Carlos <b><u>Fuentes</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Carlos Fuentes"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One reaction to produces this functional group produces dicyclohexyleurea as a byproduct and is performed by adding DCC and DMAP to a molecule commonly-used in preparing these. These functional groups are often used as plasticizers to reduce the brittleness of polyvinyl chloride. Peracids are applied to ketones to produce this functional group in the Baeyer-Villiger Oxidation. In one reaction, this functional group is formed after a water molecule leaves a tetrahedral intermediate. In biology, fats are lengthy examples of this type of functional group. These functional groups can be formed by taking a carboxylic acid and replacing the hydrogen of the hydroxide group with a hydrocarbon chain. Cyclic examples are called lactones. For 10 points, name these functional groups created in a reaction named for Fischer, which have a sweet smell.", "answer": "esters", "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>esters</u></b>", "acceptable": ["esters"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This character claims \"I have a kind of alacrity in sinking.\" He is told \"the world's mine oyster\" after refusing to lend Pistol a penny. In one monologue, he rhetorically asks \"can honor set a leg\" or \"take away the grief of a wound\"? When he is given a military command, this character impresses wealthy merchants, who bribe him. He has a circle of friends which includes Bardolph, Peto, and Ned Poins. This character falsely claims he was robbed by a hundred men after himself robbing a group of rich pilgrims at Gad's Hill. He accuses Mistress Quickly of robbing him at the Boar's Head Inn, and in another play he attempts to woo Mistress Ford and Mistress Page. For 10 points, name this fat knight who appears in both Henry IV Part I and The Merry Wives of Windsor.", "answer": "Sir John Falstaff ", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Sir John Falstaff</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Sir John Falstaff"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "During this king's rule, the Battle of Pinkie Cleugh was fought. One rebellion during this man's rule, which ended at the Battle of Sampford Courtenay, was led by Henry Bray and Sir Arundell and began after the passage of the First Act of Uniformity. The Prayerbook Rebellion occurred during this king's rule. This man signed the execution order for Thomas Seymour, who was the brother of the head of this king's regency council, Edward Seymour, who was overthrown by John Dudley following Kett's rebellion. During this king's rule, Thomas Cranmer introduced the Book of Common Prayer. The War of the Rough Wooing was fought over this man's potential marriage to Mary, Queen of Scots. For 10 points, name this British monarch who succeeded Henry VIII and who died before coming of age.", "answer": "Edward VI [prompt on Edward]", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Edward VI</u></b> [prompt on <u>Edward</u>]", "acceptable": ["Edward VI"], "promptable": ["Edward"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Strict adherents of this faith are allowed to eat but not to pick melons. In this faith, the union of Naimrael and Ashaklun created Adam and Eve, who is eternally punished. The founder of this religion was ordered to proclaim it at age 24 by the spirit Al-Tawm. Intelligence and reason are among this religion's \"five limbs.\" Members of this faith who followed its doctrines less strictly are called Hearers. It taught a severe asceticism, which included total abstinence from sex, even in marriage, and frequent fasting. This faith, which influenced the Paulicians and Cathars, holds that light was imprisoned inside Adam, and its founder is known as the Apostle of Light. This religion was denounced as a Christian heresy by its former adherent, St. Augustine. For 10 points, name this syncretic religion with an emphasis on the dualism between forces of light and the darkness of the world.", "answer": "Manichaeism", "category": "Religion", "subcategory": "Religion", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Manichaeism</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Manichaeism"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In one incident from this event, visitors dancing with women who wore whalebone corsets hypothesized that those women's rib cages were on the outside of their body. This event led to the employment of such advanced scientists as Dr. Nikolaas Bidloo, Dr. Robert Erskine, and the engineer John Perry. The leader of this event worked as a shipbuilder in a small house in Zaandam that now bears his name. Publicly led by Franz Lefort, this event failed to gather support for a crusade against the Ottoman Empire. It was prematurely cut off by news of the revolt of the Streltsy, and after the return of its participants, the beards of the boyars were shaven off. For 10 points, name this 1697-1698 event, in which the tsar of Russia traveled the continent in disguise to Westernize his country.", "answer": "Peter the Great's Grand Embassy through Europe [or equivalents, like Peter the Great's trip through Europe or Eurotrip: Meet the Ruskies]", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Peter the Great's Grand Embassy through Europe</u></b> [or <b><u>equivalents, like Peter the Great's trip through Europe</u></b> or <b><u>Eurotrip: Meet the Ruskies</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Peter the Great's Grand Embassy through Europe", "equivalents, like Peter the Great's trip through Europe", "Eurotrip: Meet the Ruskies"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "By examining the Hopi rain dance, this man showed how rituals could have \"latent functions\" like group solidarity in addition to their more overt \"manifest functions.\" His contributions to the sociology of science include describing a process by which an idea becomes so commonly known that its originator is forgotten, which he termed \"obliteration by incorporation.\" He championed the use of empirical data in sociology to ground theories of the \"middle range.\" This man argued that when people accepted society's placement of meaning in wealth but lacked legitimate means to attain it, the resulting anomie could lead them to commit crime. He coined the term \"role model\" and helped develop \"strain theory.\" For 10 points, name this sociologist who wrote Social Theory and Social Structure and coined the term \"self-fulfilling prophecy.\"", "answer": "Robert King Merton", "category": "Social Science", "subcategory": "Social Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Robert King Merton</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Robert King Merton"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "These objects were claimed to be associated with nearby galaxies by Harold Arp. Maarten Schmidt, who also discovered that these objects were more common in the early universe, and Bev Oke discovered the first type of this object, which was called 3C 273. The suppression of wavelengths below the Lyman Alpha line in these object's spectra is known as the Gunn-Peterson trough. Gavitational lensing was first confirmed by the \"twin\" version of these objects and further verified by Einstein's Cross. These objects are powered by accretion disks and exhibit the highest redshift in the known universe. For 10 points, name these highly energetic radio sources found at the center of early galaxies.", "answer": "Quasar", "subcategory": "Other Science", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Quasar</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Quasar"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}], "bonuses": []}